Sharada Sharma

Bengaluru, India, 560097

Mobile: 8712788651

E-mail: sharada8@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Organized and dependable candidate for medical documentation specialist/training specialist, who is successful at managing multiple priorities with a positive attitude and willingness to take on added responsibilities to meet team goals. More than 13+ years' experience in medical transcription as well as real-time medical scribing/documentation for 8 years. Also, I managed a team as a team lead in CTS for 1 year.

Experience:

June 19, 2023 – August 22, 2024: Team Lead at Cognizant Technology Solutions - Bengaluru, India

- Managing the day-to-day activities of the team.
- Creating an inspiring team environment with an open communication culture
- Setting clear team goals and motivating the team to achieve organizational goals.
- Delegating tasks to team members.
- Conducting training of team members to maximize their potential.

September 2015 - June 2023: Medical Documentation Specialist at OG Healthcare Pvt Ltd - Bengaluru, India

- Charted patient encounters by recording information such as diagnosis, treatments, and prescriptions.
- Reviewed outpatient records and interpreted documentation to identify diagnoses and procedures.
- Documented complete information about examinations, treatment plans, lab results, and other details directly into charts.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and a fast-paced atmosphere. ☐ Used coordination and planning skills to achieve results according to schedule. ☐ Worked to maintain outstanding attendance record, consistently arriving to work ready to start immediately.

September 2021 - October 2021: Psychology Intern (remote) at Rebuilding Minds - New Delhi, India

- Cultivated and maintained relationships in culturally diverse communities.
- Remained energetic and demonstrated passion for helping clients by applying active listening.
- Defined core problems and determined key strategies for investigating and remediating concerns.
- Identified psychological, emotional, or behavioural issues, and diagnosed disorders theoretically during the training, using information obtained from evaluation techniques.

April 2008 - August 2015: Home-Based Medical Transcriptionist at Acusis Software India Pvt Ltd – Coimbatore, India

- Started working as home based with experience of more than 7 years as medical transcriptionist then transitioned to editing formats and directly send the speech recognition files to clients on time.
- Learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions, and make decisions.
- Transcribe and edit recorded or written material, including operative reports discharge summaries, patient history and examinations, physician letters and notes and pharmacy, rehabilitation, and x-ray reports.
- Verify accuracy of patient information such as name and identification number verify accuracy of transcription for correct punctuation, grammar, and spelling.

March 2002 - June 2007: Medical Transcriptionist at Vasant Scribes Pvt Ltd - Hyderabad, India

- Received on-job training in English, medical terminology, listening skills, typing practice, and transcription.
- Attended training associated with role to improve skills and boost speed.
- Demonstrated excellent skills to understand diverse accents and dialects.
- Applied medical terminology related to provider-specific treatments and techniques.
- Recorded information using word processing, dictation and transcription software and equipment.
- Reviewed patient charts for accuracy, correcting grammar, and syntax errors before submission to clinic
- Identified and rectified inconsistencies, deficiencies, and discrepancies in medical documentation.
- Followed all HIPAA rules and regulations regarding patient confidentiality.

June 1999 - November 2001: Teacher at St. Ayesha High School and Nooria Junior

College - Hyderabad, India

- I taught Science, Social, English, and Hindi to junior and high school students.
- I also taught Commerce and Civics to junior college students.
- Addressed consistent behaviour problems with students, parents, and senior school staff.
- Fostered positive and pleasant classroom culture while maintaining learning development goals.
- Evaluated students' academic and social growth, kept appropriate records, and prepared progress reports to gauge performance.
- Organized laboratory activities, prepared lectures, and design experiments for optimum learning
 □ Developed communicative relationships with students and parents to support learning. □
 Assessed and improved lesson plans through implementation and experimentation □ Talked with students in need of extra attention and made plans to assist with concerns.

Skills:

- Great typing skills of not less than 65 wpm.
- Medical chart documentation and thorough knowledge of medical transcription guidelines and practices and ability to use designated reference materials.
- Deep knowledge of medical terminology. anatomy and physiology. and the various medical specialties as required in areas of responsibility.
- Excellent communication skills (both verbal and written) necessary to perform the essential functions of the position (including but not limited to English usage, grammar, punctuation, and sentence structure).
- Ability to work and communicate in a positive and cooperative manner with management and supervisory staff, and co-workers.
- Uncommon ability to understand diverse accents and dialects and varying dictation styles.

Education:

July 2019 – November 2021: Jain University, Center for Distance Education Bengaluru, KA

Master of Science Psychology {with Dissertation in Perceived Stress and Quality of Life of Working Individuals During Current Pandemic (COVID-19)}

June 1992 - May 1994: Kendriya Vidyalaya CRPF, Barkas Hyderabad, TG

CBSE Senior Secondary School (Class 12th)

Subjects: Biology, Physics, Chemistry, English, Hindi, PE

May 1992: Kendriya Vidyalaya CRPF, Barkas Hyderabad, TG

CBSE, Secondary School (Class 10th)

Subjects: Science, Social Science, English, Hindi, Arts, PE

Languages

- Hindi and Bhojpuri Native languages
- English Proficient

Hobbies/Interests

- Reading books
- Pursuing new online and self-study courses
- Listening to podcasts
- Watching movies and series
- Traveling and exploring new places
- Observing people